Robert Pakai

eMail: pakairobert@yahoo.com

Mobile: +40(0)766754071

Location: Cluj-Napoca, Romania

SUMMARY

I have 12+ years of experience in Linux/Unix system administration working as a Linux Engineer/SysOps and DevOps roles.

During this last 5+ years I accumulated experience in Cloud Computing using different vendors, mainly AWS, Oracle and GCP occasionaly, Using the following configuration management tools: Ansible, Chef and Terraform (terragrunt) for infrastructure as a code and Jenkins for automation created and maintained updated CI/CD pipelines.

I have 7+ years of experience in the networking field, configured Cisco routers/switches and DNS/DHCP servers and other networking related tools like OpenVPN.

3+ year of experience in VoIP filed installed, configured and maintained software switches like Asterisk and FreeSwitch.

I like to learn programing languages and I would like to consolidate my knowledge in Bash/Python languages.

SKILLS

Languages/Technologies

• Good knowledge in:

- Linux/Unix (Debian, Ubuntu, RedHat Ent, CentOS, FreeBSD)
- Docker, Docker Swarm
- Kubernetes
- Ansible, Chef, Puppet
- Terraform (terragrunt)
- Jenkins, Gitlab
- Bash/Python scripting
- Networking: Routing, switching, IPSec, VPN, Firewalls, IDS/IPS (Snort), DNS/DHCP (CCNA certified in 2010)
- WWW (Apache, Nginx, Tomcat)
- Firewall (iptables,pf,ipfw)
- Installing applications from source code (make, gcc, ant, javac)
- Load balancers: BigIP5, Foundry,
- VoIP technologies (Asterisk, Freeswitch), equipments (Xorcom, Digium, AudioCodes)
- Open LDAP directory, Samba
- OpenStack (Cloud Computing)
- Corosync/Pacemaker (HA architecture)
- HaProxy, keepalived
- Java

Software skills:

- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle
- Platforms: Windows, Linux/Unix, MacOS

Applications:

- Development tools Eclipse, NetBeans, Visual Studio Code
- Git, GitHub, SVN
- Monitoring tools: Cacti, Nagios, SNMP, Zabbix, Grafana, NewRelic, Prometheus
- Virtualization: OpenStack, WMVare, VirtualBox, ESXi
- Network Attached Storage: EMC, OpenFiler, FreeNAS, SAMBA, FTP (vsftp, ProFTP)

Experiences

DevOps

eMag Romania

2022 March - Present

My task is to create, test CI/CD pipelines in Gitlab to install helm-based chart in existing on-premise production and development Kubernetes clusters.

Create/maintain terraform code for Nomad jobs based on docker driver.

Help development teams to docker-ize legacy applications using gitlab pipeline and write different terraform code for elasticsearch indices and nomad clusters.

Maintain Gitlab server

SRE

2021 June - 2022 March

Oracle

One of my tasks it was to help with the migration of internal legacy email systems to the new Oracle cloud-based Email Delivery System and latter own the whole Email Delivery System used for internal applications and notifications

Create and maintain new requests for network flows, security groups for internal applications.

Update and maintain certificates for internal application

Maintain Terraform Gitlab pipelines for new and existing network security groups and network flows.

DevOps

2020 December - 2021 June

Frequentis

My task it was to create and test Jenkins pipelines wich created ISO files with the MosaiX application deployed for air-traffic control and VoIP communications.

DevOps

2020 September - 2020 December

Endava

My task it was to create and test CI/CD pipelines written in Ansible for AWS cloud infrastucture and automate the deployment process for different environments.

DevOps

2016 - 2020

8x8 Research and Innovation

My task is to create CI/CD pipelines and automate the deployment process of the services we are developing. I used chef/ansible/terraform and Jenkins to deploy on the existing infrastructure AWS, Kubernetes and on premise VM's

DevOps

2015 - 2016

Endava

My task was to create and automate the deployment of the services using chef on the existing on premise infrastructure and AWS. Later participated in the migration process from AWS to Verizon Enterprise Cloud. Other contribution was to install and configure FreeIPA server/client for centralized login on RedHat/CentOS servers. We started to use docker for some services and the developers started to create microservices from monolithic applications.

DevOps

2014 - 2015

Yardi

My task is to deploy OpenStack on the existing infrastructure. After the deploy we start to migrate the staging and development servers in the cloud and make the application cloud ready then start migrating the production servers in the cloud infrastructure. In this deploy I used the following technologies: for HA part corosync/pacemaker, drbd, haproxy. For the operating system I used ubuntu14.0 LTS. And the OpenStack version is HAVANA. On the application my task is to migrate from Gentoo servers to Ubuntu using CI/CD tools (Jenkins, Chef). Other task that I had is to make back-up and monitor OpenStack and services.

System Engineer 2012 – 2014

SC SoftVision SRL

From September 2013 part of the "Cloud Engineering Team" we deploy a private cloud for an important client of our company. The private cloud use open source technologies software like OpenStack and Ubuntu/RedHat Enterprise operating systems. My role is to design and install and configure the networking part. Write puppet modules to help to install the necessary software on the systems. Configure some of the networking services to offer HA (High Availability) using corosync and pacemaker.

My task is to deploy OpenStack on the existing infrastructure. After the deploy we start to migrate the staging and development servers in the cloud and make the application cloud ready then start migrating the production servers in the cloud infrastructure. In this deploy I used the following technologies: for HA part corosync/pacemaker, drbd, haproxy. For the operating system I used ubuntu14.0 LTS. And the OpenStack version is HAVANA. On the application my task is to migrate from Gentoo servers to Ubuntu. The site written in perl with mason framework.

(March 2012 - Aug 2013) Part of Nokia DevOps team. My role is to install, configure, manage existing laboratory environment and also deploy new software releases first in QA and Test the in PRODUCTION environment. I have two laboratory in maintenance which is composed from one at SoftVision and the second one in USA Atlanta. My responsibility is to install upgrade and prepare new linux system for developers and performance testing. Also we need to monitor this new server with Cacti, Nagios using SNMP. With the help of puppet I can keep the same software versions and configuration files on all servers.

Making rpm packages

Writing documents for change requests (CR).

I was in devops role in the following Nokia Sync, Mobile Cloud, and AT&T Address Book, create shell scripts to automate some administration task I installed puppet server and client on this servers and replaced some shell script to install and update software from local repository.

Periodically we run scripts that had been written to test the security of the system and if the systems are up to date and patched for know bugs and exploits.

System Engineer/Network Administrator

September 2010 – March 2012

SC Neusoft Mobile Solutions SRL, Romania

- My role was install and manage the company server room with 25 linux servers and the internal network. On this servers was the company webpage, an internal DNS/DHCP, and other web based applications (PHP, Tomcat) for the company costumers. Some of the server was installed on virtual machines using OVS as virtualization software or Esxi . For storage systems I used network storage systems (NAS)
- Other task that I had was to expand and optimize the existing networking infrastructure to suite the needs of the company. New "services" was introduced like VPN endpoints ,VoIP , and some optimizations were done by introducing load balancing, firewalls and multiple vlans and new routers and switches was purchased.
- Design and implement a VoIP system on the existing network infrastructure. I used a software based PBX (Asterisk) and a Digium E1 flux telephony card to interconnect with the provider. Some of users had hardware phones (Cisco 7960, cell phones with VoIP capabilities Nokia, Samsung, Iphone) and others used softphones like X-lite, 3CX and others.
- create and maintain shell scripts to automate some administration task of the telephony system and the webservers and backup servers.

System Engineer/Network Administrator/Support

October 2005 – September 2010 SC SilverLine Networks SRL, Romania

- My responsibilities was to install and manage the company server room with linux/unix servers . On this servers was the company webpage, the customers webpages and other web based applications for the company costumers.
- Expand and optimize the existing networking infrastructure to suite the needs of the company, new "services" was introduced like vpn ,VoIP ,firewalls, multiple vlans, making bash scripts for network traffic monitoring to report the amount of traffic what was used by customer for billing system.

- Open source "Round Cube" webmail installation customization and maintenance for the company and their B2B customers
- Designed and implemented a software PBX for a big local shopping center "Polus Center". This was based on Asterisk software PBX with Digium E1/T1 cards on the server. I used AudioCodes, Xorcom devices at the customer side. Custom scripts was made to provide billing capabilities to the system.
- we provided support on e-mail, phone and on-site for the company B2B customers.

System Engineer/Network Administrator October 2004 – September 2004 SC Medica M3 SRL, Romania

- My role was to install and maintain the company webserver. I used PHP, HTML, CSS, MySQL, JavaScript and the tool was Eclipse also my role was to implement required feature and functionality.
- create and writed shell scripts to automate backups system.
- designed and implemented vpn system for the company to provide remote assistance to the company branches.

Education
Technical University of Cluj-Napoca, Bachelor degree in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science 2003
Spoken/Written languages:
Hungarian (mother thong)
Romanian (advanced)
English (medium)
German (beginner)

ACHIEVEMENTS

Awarded with 4th place on the National Electronic Contest,

STRENGTHS

Positive attitude

High team spirit

Ambition, aspiration of continuous learning,

Calm personality

Organized

Good problem-solving skills